[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. Two answers required. These two countries debated the course of a shifting riverbed in the Chamizal dispute. An incident between these two countries began when the Dolphin refused to give a 21-gun salute. Citizens from one of these countries migrated to work as farmhands in the other under the Bracero program. The Tampico affair increased tensions between these two countries, one of which launched a “Punitive Expedition” into the other’s territory after a raid on the town of Columbus. The Zimmerman Telegram offered one of these countries a chance to regain the land it lost to the other in the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo. For 10 points, name these two countries that share a border along the Rio Grande. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America AND Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"2. John Burton analogized differing views of these entities as either billiard balls or cobwebs. The Fund for Peace publishes an index indicating the fragility, or failure, of these entities. These entities comprise the second “image of analysis” according to a book by Kenneth Waltz pairing them with Man and War. Friedrich Engels postulated that, with the rise of a socialist society, this entity would “wither away.” These entities are the primary actors in IR theory. Max Weber defined this entity as having a “monopoly on the legitimate use of force,” and they are sometimes defined as having sovereignty over a region. For 10 points, name these political entities often paired with nations. ","answer":"ANSWER: states [do not accept or prompt on “nations” or “countries”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"3. Two of the oldest texts in this genre are written in Arabic and titled Kitab al-Tabikh. A famous book in this genre is dedicated to the “peasants, fishermen, housewives, and princes” of La Belle France. A book in this genre is all that remains after a ranch burns down in the wake of Pedro and Tita de la Garza’s wedding in Laura Esquivel’s Like Water for Chocolate. It’s not a diary, but Alice B. Toklas wrote a book in this genre from which “hashish fudge” originates. A more contemporary book in this genre by Nathan Myhrvold explores modernism through molecular gastronomy. For 10 points, name this genre that includes books written by Julia Child. ","answer":"ANSWER: cookbooks [or recipe books] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"4. A museum in this European country features Louise Bourgeois’ sculpture of a spider, Maman, and a giant Puppy made out of flowers by Jeff Koons. One of this country’s cities names an “effect” in which cultural tourism revitalizes a post-industrial city. Along with glass and limestone, a museum in this country makes extensive use of its architect’s trademark thin metal shells, which resemble a ship with fish scales when seen from across the Nervión River. Frank Gehry designed a Guggenheim Museum for this country’s city of Bilbao. For 10 points, name this country home to the Prado Museum in Madrid. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spain [or España] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"5. In molecular biology, the term “densitometry” refers to quantifying band intensity in this technique with software like ImageJ. The buffer for this process contains Tris, EDTA, and either acetate or borate. The “native” form of this procedure is done without sodium dodecyl [DOH-duh-sil] sulfate. This technique is the most common way to determine the efficiency of a restriction digest. “Run to red” is a mnemonic for orienting this procedure, which is done vertically for proteins and horizontally for DNA, but almost always uses a ladder to estimate molecular weights. For 10 points, name this procedure in which an electric field drives macromolecules through a polyacrylamide or agarose matrix. ","answer":"ANSWER: gel electrophoresis [or SDS-PAGE; or a gel; accept Western blot until “Tris” is read and prompt on it afterwards] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. This figure’s only weakness is a spot on his back where a leaf once landed. This son of Hjördís uses a sword belonging to his father that was previously shattered in two by Odin. With the help of the blacksmith Regin, this figure is able to bring together the two halves of the sword Gram. This figure, who was killed by Guthorm, could understand the speech of birds after killing and tasting the blood of the dwarf-turned-dragon Fafnir. In the Volsung Saga, this hero rides through a ring of fire to rescue the Valkyrie Brunhilde. For 10 points, name this son of Sigmund from Norse mythology. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sigurd [or Siegfried] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"7. This politician was manipulated by a group of industrialists known as the “seven bankers.” He resigned from office after a scandal involving the Swiss Mabetex construction firm. This politician issued vouchers to citizens as part of a “shock therapy” program designed by his prime minister Yegor Gaidar. This politician gave a defiant speech atop a tank during the August Coup. Oligarchs like Boris Berezovsky benefited from the privatization policies implemented by this president, who gained prominence after resigning from Mikhail Gorbachev’s cabinet. For 10 points, name this first president of post-Soviet Russia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boris Yeltsin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. This element, which was first isolated from salt water as an orange brown liquid, was named for its foul smell. For 10 points, name this halogen that is liquid at standard temperature. ","answer":"ANSWER: bromine [or Br] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"9. At the climax of The League of Extraordinary Gentlemen: Century, a thinly-veiled parody of this character morphs into an eye-covered giant and is stopped from destroying London by Mary Poppins. This character asks Ebony Dark’ness Dementia Raven Way to call him “Vampire” in the online novel My Immortal. In a Neil Cicierega video, this character and his namesake “Puppet Pals” search for the source of a “Mysterious Ticking Noise.” This character’s son, Albus Severus, uses a time-turner to prevent Cedric Diggory’s death in a play titled for this man and the Cursed Child. For 10 points, name this wizard protagonist of a J. K. Rowling series. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harry Potter [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"0. This character’s fate is the subject of a Lu Xun [SHOON] speech whose title asks “what happens after [this character] leaves home?” This character responds “the most wonderful thing of all would have to happen” to a question posed by a man who often calls her “little squirrel” and “little skylark.” This character, who lies about not eating macaroons, is blackmailed by Krogstad for taking a bank loan under her father’s name to fund a trip to Italy. At the end of a play, this friend of Christine Linde realizes she’s been living with a “stranger” for “eight whole years.” For 10 points, what woman slams the door on her husband Torvald at the end of Henrik Ibsen’s play A Doll’s House? ","answer":"ANSWER: Nora Helmer [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. This minor planet is the only dwarf planet within the orbit of Neptune. For 10 points, name this largest object in the asteroid belt, which is named for the Roman goddess of agriculture. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ceres "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"2. This city’s Catholic government was bloodlessly overtaken by Protestants in the 1578 Alteratie. A Charles Mackay book discusses how a trend in this city began due to a mosaic virus that caused an object to change colors. The statues of this city’s Oude Kerk were destroyed by an iconoclastic mob during the Beeldenstorm. This city, which was gripped by “Tulip mania” in 1637, was the site of the world’s first central bank, as well as the world’s first stock exchange. Like Utrecht and Antwerp, this capital city would be underwater if not for an elaborate system of dikes. For 10 points, name this capital city that was the European headquarters of the Dutch East India Company. ","answer":"ANSWER: Amsterdam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"3. One section of this text notes that “everything is foreseen, yet free will is given.” An influential commentary on one section of this text includes a list of thirteen “principles of faith.” A passage in this text questions “if I am not for myself, who will be for me?” and asks “if not now, when?” The two versions of this text are named for Babylon and Jerusalem. The Pirkei Avot is found in the first section of this text, which was organized into six orders by Hillel. This text consists of the Mishnah and the Gemara. For 10 points, name this key text of Rabbinic Judaism that consists of oral commentaries on Jewish law. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Talmud [prompt on Mishnah or Gemara before mention by asking, “what larger text is that a part of?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"4. This historical figure examines a tapestry manufactory in a work depicting him “Visiting the Gobelins Factory.” Gian Lorenzo Bernini created a bust of this man, as well as a poorly received equestrian statue depicting him. A couple watch a portrait of this man being packed away in the painting Gersaint’s Shop Sign. Nicolas Poussin influenced the namesake style of this person, who employed Charles Le Brun as a court painter. This person holds a sceptre and flaunts his muscular legs in a portrait by Hyacinthe Rigaud. For 10 points, name this patron of 17th-century French art who commissioned the Palace of Versailles, nicknamed the “Sun King.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis XIV [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"5. Edward Bulwer-Lytton criticized a scene in which this character reconnects with his widowed and remarried childhood crush. Jack Maggs searches for a re-imagined version of this character in a Peter Carey novel. In that novel, Maggs represents this character’s benefactor, who became rich after working as a sheep farmer in Australia, the convict Abel Magwitch. This character’s love Estella is raised in Satis House, which is filled with stopped clocks to commemorate the failed wedding of Miss Havisham. For 10 points, name this orphaned protagonist of Charles Dickens’ Great Expectations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Philip “Pip” Pirrip [accept any underlined part] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. In a 1964 referendum, citizens of this country voted to return the “lost counties” to the Kingdom of Bunyoro. The Common Man’s Charter codified the nationalization policies of this country’s “Move to the Left.” A leader of this country was exiled to Saudi Arabia after he attempted to annex a neighboring country’s Kagera region. Thousands of Asians were expelled from this country by a dictator who welcomed a hijacked plane full of Jewish hostages to this country’s Entebbe airport. That dictator of this country declared himself the “Last King of Scotland.” For 10 points, name this country once ruled by Idi Amin from Kampala. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Uganda "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"7. Wires are often “coupled” with respect to this phenomenon in order to limit power loss along the line. This process causes eddy currents which transform energy into heat because they resist the direction of change, as described by Lenz’s law. Transformers often use a coil named for this phenomenon in order to step up voltage. Solenoids cause this phenomenon within themselves. The electromotive force is proportional to the negative of the derivative of the magnetic flux with respect to time, according to Faraday’s law of this phenomenon. For 10 points, name this phenomenon in which a voltage is produced across a conductor due to a change in the magnetic field. ","answer":"ANSWER: electromagnetic induction "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"8. A character in this novel states “I seed de beginnin, en now I sees de endin” after she is moved to tears by a sermon. A woman in this novel who smells like honeysuckle scolds her brother for kissing the “dirty girl” Natalie, even though she herself has “muddied her drawers.” While watching golfers on his thirty-third birthday, a character in this novel is told to stop “moaning” by his caretaker Luster. On June 2, 1910, a Harvard student in this novel jumps off a bridge while thinking about his sister Caddy. For 10 points, name this novel narrated by Jason. Benjy and Quentin Compson, written by William Faulkner. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sound and the Fury "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"9. Towards the end of this piece, the orchestra pauses, then blasts a dissonant, mostly whole-tone chord topped with an A for two bars; the orchestra then builds into its final reprisal of this piece’s “Stride” theme. It’s not by Copland, but in a 1942 recording of this composition, the opening “Ritornello” theme is played by Benny Goodman. Originally scored for two pianos, this piece is mostly performed as orchestrated by Ferde Grofé [“ferd gro-FE”]. This jazz-inspired piece opens with a trill followed by a long glissando in the solo clarinet. For 10 points, name this colorfully-named piece by George Gershwin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rhapsody in Blue "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"0. A text by this philosopher organizes various “instances agreeing in the form of heat” into a “table of presentation.” Denis Diderot’s taxonomy of knowledge was inspired by this philosopher’s division of the human mind into memory, imagination, and reason. An allegorical book by this philosopher is set at an ideal school on the island of Bensalem. This philosopher theorized four fallacies called the “idols” of the cave, the tribe, the theater, and the marketplace in a text proposing his namesake method. For 10 points, name this British philosopher of The New Atlantis and Novum Organum who emphasized an empiricist and inductive scientific method. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sir Francis Bacon Tiebreaker. Along with pH, this quantity is one of the axes on a diagram that maps the equilibrium phases of an aqueous system, named for Marcel Pourbaix. A formula for calculating this quantity may include the number 0.059 if a common logarithm is involved, and most often contains the term “RT over nF ln Q”. This quantity’s value is defined as zero for the production of hydrogen gas from the H+ ion. The Nernst equation calculates this quantity, which is symbolized by a script E. For 10 points, name this “potential” that represents the tendency of a species to gain electrons. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this feminine alter-ego of a male artist whose name puns on the phrase “such is life.” This alias partially titles a sculpture consisting of a birdcage filled with marble cubes and cuttlefish bones. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rrose Sélavy [accept either underline portion; or Why Not Sneeze, Rose Sélavy?; prompt on Marcel Duchamp] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Rrose Sélavy was the feminine alter-ego of Marcel Duchamp, who promoted the “anti-art” of this avant-garde European movement. Its name, allegedly chosen from a dictionary at random, translates to “hobbyhorse.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Dadaism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Duchamp stirred controversy by attempting to submit one of these objects, which he had reoriented 90 degrees and signed “R. Mutt 1917,” to New York’s Society of Independent Artists exhibit. ","answer":"ANSWER: a urinal [or toilet; do not accept or prompt on Fountain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this novel in which Bamford drives a yellow baakie. It ends with Maureen running towards a helicopter. ","answer":"ANSWER: July’s People "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Nobel laureate wrote July’s People. Jacobus finds a corpse on his farm in this author’s novel The Conservationist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nadine Gordimer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Nadine Gordimer hailed from this country, which banned July’s People after Gordimer spoke out against this country’s apartheid policy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of South Africa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these bonds that link together two amino acids. ","answer":"ANSWER: peptide bonds [or peptides; or eupeptide bonds] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Trypsin’s active site contains a catalytic triad that uses this amino acid as a nucleophile. Protein kinase A belongs to a group of kinase enzymes that recognize either this amino acid or threonine. ","answer":"ANSWER: serine [or Ser or S; or serine protease; or serine-threonine kinase] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Unlike trypsin, papain [“pah-PAY-en”] belongs to a class of proteases named after this amino acid. The toughness of keratin is partly due to the disulfide bonds formed by this amino acid. ","answer":"ANSWER: cysteine [or Cys; or C; or cysteine protease] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this Roman general who described his conquest of Gaul in Commentaries on the Gallic Wars. He was later stabbed to death on the Ides of March. ","answer":"ANSWER: Julius Caesar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Caesar finally subdued Vercingetorix at this battle. At this battle, Caesar built two sets of walls, one facing inwards to attack this battle’s namesake city and an outward wall to ward off Vercingetorix’s reinforcements. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alesia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Caesar quipped “alea iacta est,” or “the die is cast,” as he marched his army over this Italian river. Caesar’s crossing of this river initiated the Great Roman Civil War. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Rubicon [or the Rubico] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these people who may recall events inaccurately due to suggestibility and the misinformation effect. Loftus and Palmer demonstrated the unreliability of these people in an experiment that had patients describe the severity of a car crash. ","answer":"ANSWER: eyewitnesses [or On the Witness Stand: Essays on Psychology and Crime; accept court witnesses;] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Aside from creating Wonder Woman, Münsterberg’s student William Marston is known for championing the use of this device. Modern studies largely reject evidence provided by these devices, which determine the validity of eyewitnesses by measuring factors like blood pressure and heartbeat. ","answer":"ANSWER: lie detectors [or polygraph tests] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Münsterberg wrote a book pairing psychology with this sort of efficiency. This term is paired with the word “organizational” in the name of a branch of psychology that studies workplaces. ","answer":"ANSWER: industrial [or industrial efficiency; or industrial and organizational psychology] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this region of the body where a colored dot known as a bindi is often worn by Hindu and Jain women, traditionally to represent concealed wisdom or the “third eye.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the forehead [prompt on the face or head] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Hindu women receive the sindoor, a streak of vermillion across the forehead and hair, following one of these events. During this event, Hindus traditionally take seven steps around a holy fire as part of the ritual of Saptapadi. ","answer":"ANSWER: marriage [or wedding] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] In preparation for weddings, Hindu women will often host gatherings to be adorned in an ornate form of body art known by this name, that utilizes a brown dye obtained from the dried leaves of a certain plant. ","answer":"ANSWER: mehndi [or mehendi; or henna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this head of the Second Bank of the United States who deliberately raised interest rates to cause a recession in an attempt to stop Andrew Jackson from shuttering the Second Bank. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicholas Biddle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Citing the Necessary and Proper Clause, this 1819 Supreme Court case affirmed the constitutionality of the Second Bank of the United States. This case’s majority opinion states “the power to tax is the power to destroy.” ","answer":"ANSWER: McCulloch v. Maryland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This longest-serving Chief Justice of the Supreme Court authored the majority opinion in McCulloch. His majority opinion in Marbury v. Madison established the principle of judicial review. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Marshall "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this type of dance performed by Bojangles and Shirley Temple on a staircase in the film The Littlest Colonel. Most of Fred Astaire’s solo dances were performed in this style of dancing. ","answer":"ANSWER: tap dance [or tap dancing] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] After she was denied service at a hotel in this South American country, Dunham helped pass a bill forbidding racial discrimination in its cities. This country is the origin of the samba and jongo dance styles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brazil "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This student of Dunham paid tribute to her in a performance titled The Magic of Katherine Dunham. He’s better known for founding a New York-based dance company and channeling spirituals and blues in his ballet Revelations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alvin Ailey "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Millennium Prize Problem concerns the equivalence of two complexity classes; it asks whether a problem that can be “quickly” verified can also be solved “quickly”. ","answer":"ANSWER: P versus NP problem [or Does P=NP?; or other answers that specify both P and NP; do not accept or prompt on just “P” or “NP”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] If P is in fact equivalent to NP, this technique of translating readable data to apparent nonsense for secure communication purposes would break. Its “public key” variant may use the RSA system. ","answer":"ANSWER: cryptography [or cryptology; or encryption; or cryptosystems; or public-key cryptography; accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] A problem C belongs to this complexity class if C is in NP and every NP problem can be reduced to C in polynomial time. Finding a Hamiltonian path for a graph is a classic problem in this complexity class. ","answer":"ANSWER: NP-completeness "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this Dutch physicist who introduced a and b parameters in his namesake equation of state for gases. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johannes Diderik van der Waals "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Van der Waals’ equation of state treats real gases, as opposed to this type of gas, which is represented as point particles that have perfectly elastic collisions. This kind of gas names a “law” that states PV equals nRT. ","answer":"ANSWER: ideal gases "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The law of corresponding states says that all gases have roughly the same value for this quantity at the same reduced pressure and temperature. This quantity, symbolized Z, describes the deviation of a gas from ideal behavior. ","answer":"ANSWER: compressibility factor [or compression factor; prompt on gas deviation factor] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this sculptor from Greek myth who fell in love with one of his own statues, Galatea. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pygmalion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Pygmalion hailed from this island, which was also the birthplace of Adonis and Teucer. According to legend, this island’s city of Paphos was founded by Pygmalion’s son. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cyprus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Greek goddess of love had a cult center at Paphos. When Pygmalion fell in love with his own statue, he prayed to this wife of Hephaestus, who agreed to bring the statue to life. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aphrodite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] A descriptivist theory of names was put forth by this thinker in his book A System of Logic. He’s better known for advancing the “greatest-happiness principle” in his Utilitarianism. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Stuart Mill "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This philosopher rebuked Mill’s theory by proposing a distinction between “sense” and “reference.” He illustrated the former with the example of how both Hesperus and Phosphorus refer to the planet Venus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gottlob Frege [or Friedrich Ludwig Gottlob Frege] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Later philosophers described “fixing” and “borrowing” in a theory of reference described by this process. Mill’s five methods of induction illustrate this process, which Aristotle divided into material, formal, efficient, and final types. ","answer":"ANSWER: causation [or causal reference; or causes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this realm that was elevated to an empire by its Habsburg archdukes after they dissolved the Holy Roman Empire. It was ruled in a dual monarchy with Hungary. ","answer":"ANSWER: Austria [or Austrian Empire; accept Austro-Hungarian Empire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] At the Congress of Vienna, this reactionary Austrian statesman formed the German Confederation to ensure Austria’s continued domination of the former Holy Roman Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Klemens von Metternich "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Under Metternich, Austria did not join this economic union, founded by Prussia in 1834, that limited tariffs on trade between German-speaking states. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zollverein "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this color. This color reminds Celie of her romantic partner Shug Avery, which inspires her to decorate her home entirely in red and this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: purple [or The Color Purple; do not accept or prompt on shades of purple like “violet”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The Color Purple was written by this woman. She dedicated that novel’s sequel, Possessing the Secret of Joy, to the “blameless vulva.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Alice Walker "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] In the 1970s, Alice Walker edited and contributed content to this feminist magazine, which was co-founded by Gloria Steinem. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ms. magazine "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these theoretical subatomic particles that are believed to move faster than the speed of light. ","answer":"ANSWER: tachyons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Tachyons have an imaginary value for this quantity. According to Newton’s second law, force is equal to this quantity times acceleration. ","answer":"ANSWER: mass "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Tachyons violate this principle, which describes how phenomena cannot be created from things that happen outside the light cone before them. ","answer":"ANSWER: causality [or causation; or cause; accept word forms "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this opera, based on a Nikolai Leskov novel, that was attacked in the article “Muddle Instead of Music.” In this opera, Katerina feeds her husband Zinovy poison mushrooms so she can marry the merchant Boris. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District [or Lady Macbeth of Mtsensk] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Soviet composer described his 5th Symphony as a reply to the “justified criticism” received by his Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District. He also composed the Leningrad Symphony. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dmitri (Dmitriyevich) Shostakovich "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The ostinato “invasion theme” of Shostakovich’s Leningrad Symphony is accompanied by this percussion instrument. This instrument maintains a constant ostinato throughout Ravel’s Bolero. ","answer":"ANSWER: snare drum [prompt on drum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this short story in which Gabriel Conroy learns of his wife Mary’s youthful love affair with Michael Furey. It is the last and longest story collected in Dubliners. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Dead” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This author included “The Dead” alongside “Araby” and “Ivy Day in the Committee Room” in his short story collection Dubliners. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Joyce "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] At the end of “The Dead,” Gabriel Conroy notes that this substance is “general all over Ireland.” In the story’s last sentence, this substance is described “faintly falling” over “all the living and the dead.” ","answer":"ANSWER: snow [or snowflakes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this community of American-based Mennonites who avoid using modern technology and wear 18th century clothing. Their largest settlement is in Lancaster County, Pennsylvania. ","answer":"ANSWER: Amish [or Pennsylvania Dutch] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Some Amish communities have begun using modern power tools to construct these buildings, which are sometimes built in under an hour by Amish during a communal ceremony known as their “raising.” ","answer":"ANSWER: barns "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Most Amish teenagers experiment with modern technology as part of this Amish coming-of-age period, during which they are separated from their families and allowed to explore the outside world. ","answer":"ANSWER: rumpsringa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this cult leader who moved his organization, the People’s Temple, from the United States to a compound in Guyana. He and his followers drank flavor aid laced with cyanide in a 1978 mass suicide. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jim Jones "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Before they moved to Guyana, Jones and his followers were based in this Northern California city, where they helped elect Harvey Milk as this city’s first gay elected official. ","answer":"ANSWER: San Francisco, California "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The Jonestown massacre occurred shortly after the People’s Temple ambushed this congressman, who had inspected Jonestown a day prior. He is the only congressman to have been killed in the line of duty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Leo Ryan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this home country of the Andalusian-born Juan Ramón Jiménez. This country’s Baroque authors included the rival poets Luis de Góngora and Francisco de Quevedo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spain [or España] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Jiménez moved from Seville to Madrid at the behest of this Nicaraguan poet, who pioneered modernismo with his collection Azul… . ","answer":"ANSWER: Rubén Darío "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Dario was first championed by the critic Juan Valera, an author whose novel Pepita Jiménez is associated with the Spanish branch of this movement that depicted everyday life. French writers in this style, which is not Naturalism, included Stendhal and Honoré de Balzac. ","answer":"ANSWER: realism [or realist literature] Tiebreaker. As part of a failed coup d’etat, planes bombed the Plaza de Mayo during one of this man’s rallies. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this husband of Evita whose presidency was built on the support of working-class descamisados, or “shirtless ones.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Juan Domingo Peron "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Peron’s death ushered in a military takeover of this South American country, whose leaders murdered dissidents in the Dirty War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Argentina "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] During the Dirty War, a group of these people named for the Plaza de Mayo wore white scarves to protest the abduction and murder their “disappeared” relatives. ","answer":"ANSWER: mothers [or grandmothers; accept equivalents to “mother” like madre or mom; prompt on women or girls] EXTRA For 10 points each, answer the following about South American natives: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Yanomami tribes live deep in this country’s Amazon rainforest, where they have been encroached upon by garimpeiro gold miners. Through the practice of cunhadismo, this country’s coastal Tupi people intermarried with Portuguese settlers, but largely died out due to disease. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brazil "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The indigenous Guarani language is the most widely spoken language in this country. During the rule of Alfredo Stroessner, this country’s Aché people were openly massacred and enslaved. ","answer":"ANSWER: Paraguay "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] These natives under Lautaro resisted Pedro de Valdivia in the 16th century and remained largely independent until the 19th-century occupation of Araucanía. These natives name an ongoing conflict against Chile’s government. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mapuche The Aborigine Bungaree accompanied this captain on his journeys as a guide and interpreter. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this explorer who first circumnavigated Australia and identified it as a continent. His suggestion to name the continent “Australia” was formally adopted by Governor Lachlan Macquarie. ","answer":"ANSWER: Matthew Flinders "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This captain of the HMS Endeavor christened Botany Bay and made the first circumnavigation of New Zealand. This explorer died in a scuffle in Hawaii after abducting King Kalaniʻōpuʻu. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Cook "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. He named the new land for this country’s province of Zeeland, though it didn’t stick. ","answer":"ANSWER: Netherlands"}]
